Exactly three years ago,
三年前的這個時候
I promised you a president
我承諾過 要做一位
who feels your pain and who shares your dreams.
體恤民情的總統與大家擁有同一個夢
I want to talk to you about a fundamental threat
我要告訴大家 現在有一個情況
to American democracy.
從根本上對美國的民主形成了威脅
抱歉 汽油提供直到下月
For the the first time in the history of our country,
大多數人認為 未來的五年較之於以往的五年
a majority of our people believe
日子會更不好過
that the next five years
這在我國歷史上
will be worse than the past five years.
實屬首次
片名：美國行動
Alpha, Alpha 15 uh, tell us your route course.
呼叫A15航班 請報告你們當前的路線
根據真實事件改編
Yeah, Alpha, Alpha 15 at November for time at Delta Delta.
報告 A15航班在路線N上
Shit.
媽的
Howdy, folks.
夥計們 你們好
I apologize for the delay.
很抱歉 我們遲了一會
We're at number 11 for take off.
我們是第11架起飛的飛機
We'll try to make it up in the air.
我們爭取路上飛快點
Just wake me up over Texas.
到德克薩斯州把我叫醒
環球航空公司
自動駕駛
關閉
Apologies from the flight deck.
我代表機組人員表達歉意
Just a little bit of turbulence.
只是遇上了一些氣流而已
Thank you all for flying TWA tonight.
感謝各位今晚乘坐環球航空公司航班
Welcome to Baton Rouge.
歡迎來到巴吞魯日
The people's choice.
人們的選擇
...and for you history buffs is in Lousiana.
在路易斯安那
- Hey, Luce. - Uh, back here.
- 嘿 露西 - 我馬上就來
Thank you for flying TWA.
感謝您乘坐環球航空公司航班
Welcome to Vancouver.
歡迎來到溫哥華
Welcome to Bakersfield.
歡迎來到貝克斯菲爾德
Welcome to Denver.
歡迎來到丹佛
I hope they put us up at the Holiday Inn tonight.
我希望今晚他們能讓我們住假日酒店
Those little cocktail gals are on fire.
那些性感的小妞
As soon as they see a man in uniform,
看到穿制服的帥哥
panties come off.
就按捺不住了
Mmm, mmm.
嗯
Thanks, Bobby.
謝了 鮑比
Hi, Chivas on the rocks.
嗨 我要一杯芝華士酒 加冰
Barry.
巴裏
What's that?
你是哪位？
Barry Seal.
你是巴裏·希爾吧
That's right.
對
You have a...
你是不是
drop off and pick up service here every other Thursday.
每週四都來這接活
Cuban exiles.
一些在古巴的流亡者
They pay commercial pilots to smuggle homegrown contraband
付錢給民航飛行員讓他們把本地的違禁品
through Canadian hubs. Vancouver, Montreal.
帶到加拿大溫哥華
Right?
沒錯吧？
I'm sorry, I don't know what you're talkin' about.
抱歉 我不知道你在說什麼
- No? - No.
- 不知道？- 不知道
You're smuggling cigars.
你在走私雪茄吧
Your have an interesting file, Barry.
巴裏 你的檔案很有趣
File?
什麼檔案？
Starts off with a bang.
出道時就聲名遠揚
Top of your class in the Civil Air Patrol.
在民間空中巡邏隊開設的培訓班中 名列前茅
Youngest pilot in TWA history.
環球航空歷史上最年輕的飛行員
You were going places.
你閱歷頗豐啊
What is goin' on here?
這是什麼情況啊？
Revolution is in the air, Barry.
巴裏 有一場革命即將到來
Central America, right now.
目前 我們在美洲中部
We're building nations down there, Barry.
準備建立一個國家
We're building nations.
建立一個國家呢 巴裏
It's America at its fuckin' finest.
我們國家就擅長幹這個
And we could use someone like you.
我們用的上你這樣的人
God damn.
我的天
You're CIA.
你是中情局的吧
Shhh.
噓
Holy shit.
我的天
Hot damn. Look at her.
看看這玩意
Well, they uh, they tell me she's pretty fast.
他們跟我說 這玩意飛的可快了
Yeah. Yeah.
是啊
The fastest twin engine on the planet.
這是地球上飛的最快的雙引擎飛機了
I mean, shit.
哇 這玩意簡直牛了
She looks like she's goin' 300 miles an hour just sittin' there.
我感覺這玩意一小時飛個300英里完全沒問題
CIA owns this?
這是中情局的資產？
No. No.
不 不是
Uh, Independent Aviation Consultants.
我是獨立航空咨詢顧問公司的
- IAC. - Yeah.
- 獨立航空咨詢顧問公司 - 是的
What is that? What do they call one of them front goups, is it?
你們這個 他們是不是把你們機構稱作"外圍組織"？
No, no, no. It's as real as IBM.
不不不 我們是一個實體公司 就像IBM一樣
Uh-huh.
嗯
You'd run the company, but after hours, you work for us.
你負責管理那個公司 之後你就為我們幹活了
Yup.
行
It takes pictures?
這玩意是用來拍照的？
Mm-hmm. We say it collects intelligence.
用我們的話來說 它是用來"收集情報"的
Uh-huh.
嗯
Where? Russia?
我們在哪行動？俄羅斯？
Uh, south of the border. North of the equator.
國界以南 赤道以北
Let's just say uh...
就是那個我們稱作
Enemies of democracy.
"民主敵人"的那個國家
Look, the real work is covert. You understand?
我們幹的活是見不得光的 你明白吧？
- So, so uh... - "Covert".
- 所以 呃 - 見不得光啊
Anyone finds out about it, uh...
所以 要是有人發現了
Family, friends, even uh, Lucy. It's Lucy, right?
不管是你的家人 朋友 或者是露西 她是叫露西吧？
Yeah, that's right.
是的 對
That'd be a problem.
那就不太妙了
- What? - All this is legal?
- 你說什麼？- 這是合法的麼
If you're doin' it for the good guys... yeah.
是的 我們都是好人
Just don't get caught. You wanna take it for a spin?
別被抓住就行了 要不要試飛一下這玩意？
Fuck it. Take it for a fucking spin.
就這麼定了 你去試飛一下吧
I want you to take her for a spin.
動作快點吧
It's all for me.
這是為了我好
It's a new business. It's gonna be my business.
這是項新業務 這是我自己的選擇
- Okay, logistical support for airports. - That's right.
- 好吧 為機場提供後勤服務 - 沒錯
Okay. And you're callin' it IAC?
你把他稱作"獨航顧問"？
What do you know about business?
對於他的公司你瞭解多少？
You are a TWA airline pilot.
你可是一位環球航空公司的飛行員啊
That's how you support this family.
你就靠這份工作養家餬口呢
This is gonna be good for us.
這是為了我們好
What about benefits?
那其它的福利怎麼辦
Our healthcare?
醫保怎麼辦
And we have great healthcare with TWA.
環球航空的醫保制度很不錯啊
Um, you know, I'm sure that's not gonna be a problem.
這個問題不大
And what the hell does IAC mean, anyway?
再說這個"獨航顧問"到底是個什麼玩意？
Independent Aviation Consultants.
"獨立航空咨詢顧問公司"
Well, that sounds fuckin' made up, Barry.
巴裏 這玩意聽起來就像瞎編的一樣
It does?
是麼？
Flight control screen correct.
航班控制系統正常
- Warning and annunciator lights. - Check...on that.
- 警示燈和信號燈系統 - 已檢查
- Anti-skid lights. - Lights off.
- 防滑指示燈 - 已關閉
- Landing gear. - Handle's down, three green.
- 起落架 - 把手朝下 三個指示燈亮綠燈
- Speed brake lever. - Stowed.
- 速度制動桿 - 已就緒
- Thrust levers. - Cut off.
- 推進器控制桿 - 已關閉
- Engine start levers. - Cut off.
- 發動機控制桿 - 已關閉
- Snap trim panel switches. - Normal.
- 儀表盤飾板開關 - 正常
Fire warning system.
火災警告系統
Check.
已檢查
Radius transponder radar.
無線電切換成雷達
- Barry? Radius transponder radar. - Yeah, check, check.
- 巴裏？無線電切換成雷達 - 嗯嗯 已檢查
- Rudder aileron trim. - Zero zero.
- 方向舵副翼修正 - 已修正
Windows.
窗戶檢查
Closed.
已關閉
Flight attendant briefing.
空乘人員情況
Uh, Barry?
巴裏？
You gonna be all right, Jimmy.
你好好幹 吉米
Where are you where are you going?
你去哪呢？
Barry! Barry, where are you going?
巴裏 巴裏 你去哪？
Shit. I know, I know.
該死 我知道 我知道
That was bold.
我的舉動很大膽
很大膽
I do tend to leap before I look.
我經常不思考太多就做決定
Maybe uh...
也許
Maybe I should've asked a few more questions.
也許我應該再多問一下情況的
Anyways, back in '78, in uh...
那是1978年的時候吧
September? October.
大概是9月還是10月份
Anyway, it uh...
不管怎麼說
That was the day I joined the CIA.
我加入中情局的那天 可是我人生中很重要的日子
中情局
美 國
Now, in those days, the cold war was in full swing.
那時候 冷戰處於高峰期
蘇 聯
The Soviets were backing
蘇聯在美洲中部
communist insurgents all over Central America.
支持當地的共產主義叛軍
墨西哥
危地馬拉
尼加拉瓜
巴拿馬
危地
危地馬拉
The CIA wanted snaps of them insurgents.
中情局想航拍一下那些叛軍的情況
洪都拉斯
Now these pictures are sensational.
這些照片很不錯
Who's responsible?
誰負責這次行動？
They're mine.
我
- Hey, Monty. - Yeah.
- 嘿 蒙蒂 - 什麼事
Who the fuck is he?
那傢伙到底是誰？
薩爾瓦多
Oh!
噢
Oh, shit!
噢 媽的
Come on, now. Come on, now.
加把勁 加把勁
Fuck!
媽的
Woo!
喔
The people's choice.
人們的選擇
So uh, so then I show him this one.
所以呃 我給他們看了這個
And he goes uh, "Goddammit, Schafer, I didn't ask for mug shots."
他們說 "謝弗 太強了 臉的拍得很清楚"
I mean, they said they're
我是說 他們覺得
the best reconnaissance photos they have ever seen.
這是他們見過的最好的偵察照片
So does this mean I get a raise?
那這是不是就意味著 能給我加薪呢？
You're doing great.
你做的很不錯
You got a family, Schafer?
你有家人麼 謝弗？
Big push!
用力
Ah, motherfucker!
該死的
Wife, kids?
有妻子 有孩子麼？
See, I uh, I didn't tell Lucy I ain't workin' for TWA no more.
我還沒告訴露西 我已經不在環球航空公司上班了
You're serving your country.
你在為國效力啊
I am gonna need some more money at some point.
再過陣子我需要一筆錢了
You'll figure it out.
我們會搞定的
Oh, uh...
那個
We uh, we're sending you to Panama tomorrow.
明天我們要派你去巴拿馬
機密
獨立航空咨詢
顧問公司
The CIA was so happy with my work,
中情局對我做的工作很滿意
they gave me another job.
他們又給了我一份任務
巴拿馬城
Bag man.
讓我送貨
See, there was this Colonel down in Panama
在巴拿馬有一個上校
named Noriega.
叫諾列加
And he was selling the Agency's intel on all the commies down there.
他把中情局的情報賣給那裏的共產主義分子
For your friends.
這是給你朋友的
My job was just to drop off and pick up.
我的工作就是送錢拿貨
Just drop off.
送錢
And pick up.
拿貨
Right here in Baton Rogue.
就在巴吞魯日
You're listening to the best in Louisiana music.
你目前正在收聽的 是路易斯安那州最棒的音樂
- Hey, Luce, pancakes are up. - Thanks, baby.
- 嘿 露西 煎餅做好了 - 謝了 寶貝
哥倫比亞
Hola!
你們好
Uh... gasolina.
汽油
Si. Gasolina.
這兒有汽油呢
In the car.
上車吧
Hey uh...
嘿呃
A donde vamos, fellas?
夥計 這是去哪裏？
Welcome.
歡迎啊
Come on up.
上來吧
Thank you for coming to see me.
感謝你來見我啊
Sir, I... I think there's been some sort of
先生 我覺得可能
mistake here, because I...
你是搞錯了 因為我
These fellas just picked me up at the airport.
他們就這麼從機場把我接過來
No, no. No mistake.
沒搞錯
Just please... have a seat.
請坐吧
Coffee, Mr. Seal?
喝咖啡的吧 希爾先生
Dos tinticos.
來兩杯咖啡
You know my name?
你知道我是誰吧？
You're the gringo who flies to Central America every week.
你每周都開飛機到中美洲來啊
Taking pictures very low with your fancy plane.
開著飛機拍了不少照片呢
Yeah, I mean uh-uh... those photos, see I have a uh...
是這樣的 拍的那些照片
aviation company here in South America, I advise...
是我在給一個南美洲的航空公司打工 我建議
- Yes, the AIC. - IAC. Yes, Sir.
- 是叫AIC吧 - IAC 是的 先生
Or is it CIA?
還是叫CIA？
What? No, no, no. I'm just a businessman here.
什麼？不不不 我只是個商人
I'm a businessman.
我也是個商人
Imports-Exports. Cattle.
運輸牲畜啊
Horses.
馬匹啊
But now...
現在呢
Now, God above has blessed this great country with new riches,
上帝保佑我們的國家 我們有了發財的機會
Mr. Seal.
希爾先生
And you could help us.
你能幫助我們
How's that?
怎麼幫？
You know the routes.
你對航線很瞭解
You can get in and out Estados Unidos with your fancy plane.
用你那漂亮飛機把貨運進美國
What kind of riches we talkin' 'bout here?
我們這是在討論什麼呢？
Cocaine, Mr. Seal.
可卡因 希爾先生
We had a few difficulties getting our exports
把它們運到你們國內有些困難
to your country, Mr. Seal.
希爾先生
9996.
Ma'am, what's in the bag?
女士 包裏有什麼？
We decided to try new ideas.
我們決定嘗試些新辦法
We want you to take off from here.
我們想讓你直接從這
Fly directly to Miami.
運到邁阿密
We'll pay you $2,000 per kilo.
每公斤我們付你兩千美元
How much is a kilo?
一公斤是多少磅？
2.2 pounds, Mr. Seal.
一公斤等於2.2磅
$2,000...
兩千美元啊
every 2.2 pounds.
每2.2磅
I'm sorry, fellas.
很抱歉 兄弟
I didn't catch ya'll's names.
我還記不住你們的名字
Jorge Ochoa.
豪爾赫·奧喬亞
Carlos Lehder.
卡洛斯·雷德
Pablo Escobar.
帕布洛·艾斯科巴
A couple of billion dollars from now,
再多賺幾十億美金
they'd be known as the Medellin Cartel.
他們就會成為赫赫有名的麥德林販毒集團
See, back then, they're just three businessmen
但那時候 他們還只不過是三個普通商人
tryin' to figure out how to get their
在想法子把他們的貨
merchandise to the United States.
運到美國
There was just one small problem.
只有一個小問題
See, pilots, they were
在這地方起飛
killin' themselves tryin' to get off that runway.
飛行員一不小心就會出事
I see you had a few other boys try to make it outta here.
我看有幾個人想從這裏起飛
Si. Si, terrible pilots.
是啊 那些傢伙飛行技術不行
Yeah, well... I'm sure they were heavy.
對啊 我知道這些貨挺沉的
I'm sure they were heavy.
我知道這些貨挺沉的
You know, carryin' a lot of fuel to make to States...
把貨運到美國需要很多油
And merchandise and...
要裝很多貨
Yeah, you know, this airport, I mean it's...
我想說的是 這個機場
High altitude and a short runway.
海拔很高 跑道很短
I mean, shit, you got trees and mountains on both sides.
旁邊都是樹林 還有高山
Is there uh,
有沒有
Is there somewhere else I could take off from?
有沒有別的地方讓我起降？
Not where the army wouldn't notice.
其它地方會把軍方引來的
Well, uh...
那麼
Can you make the runway longer?
能把跑道加長一些麼？
They say I should get rid of you.
他們說 我應該把你送走的
That you can't do it.
說你辦不成事
- We have our people in Miami. - Yeah.
- 邁阿密那邊有我們的人 - 好
You gonna land at the Okeechobee Airport between 2:00 and 6:00 a.m.
凌晨6點至7點間 你在奧基機場著陸
Look, there's uh...
計劃有變
There's been a change of plans 'cause I ain't landin' in Miami...
因為我不能在邁阿密降落
Oh, thank you. Gracias.
謝謝
See, I ain't landin' anywhere with this stuff.
我可不打算帶著這些貨降落
That's, that's how ya'll got in trouble.
你們以前就是這樣惹上麻煩的
Now, look, just, just hear me out.
聽我說
I know Louisiana. Now, here's a map.
我瞭解路易斯安那的情況 這裏有個地圖
Now, I'm gonna drop this stuff right where "X" marks the spot.
我會把東西空投到這個標記的位置
All right? Just...
所以
What do you mean you're not gonna land, huevon?
你說你不能在那邊著陸 什麼意思？
Okay, just... Hey, come here, just...
等下 嘿過來
Look, just look at this.
來看看
Look.
看看這個
See, right here. See that there?
你看這裏 看到了吧？
Hmm.
嗯
Right there is your million-dollar door.
你那價值百萬美元的貨 就從這空投下去
All right? You just go around.
就像這樣 用膠帶捆住它
Each side...tight.
捆結實了
No, no, no. No more.
不 不 不 不能再裝了
I said no more.
我說了 不能再裝了
No mas. No mas. No mas. No mas.
不能裝了
But there's plenty of room, gringo.
飛機上還有的是地方呢 外國佬
- No, no. Si, si, Hasta arriba. - Guys, guys.
- 就是啊 還可以裝的 往上摞啊 - 各位
It ain't about room, all right? It's about weight.
這不是空間的問題 而是重量 好吧
Now, we agreed on 200, I even put on 300.
我們之前說的是裝200公斤 現在都裝了300公斤
No mas. No mas.
不能裝了 不能
Keep pushin', come on. I need all the runway I can get.
繼續走 我要足夠長的起飛距離
Keep goin', keep goin'. See that.
繼續走 繼續
Pare. Pare. Pare. Hold. Hold.
停 停 穩住 別動
Bien, bien.
行了 行了
Gracias, gracias.
謝謝 謝謝
Where the hell do you think you're going, big fella?
你要幹啥呢 大塊頭？
Come on. Out.
快點 出來
He's gonna guard the product.
他負責保護貨物
This guy's fatter than fuck.
他太胖了
I'm already 1500 pounds overweight.
運載量已經達到1500磅了
Either I fly the big fella, or I fly your product.
我要麼只運他 要麼只運貨
Good luck, hermano.
祝你好運 兄弟
God will keep you safe.
上帝保佑你平安
He ain't gonna make this runway any longer.
上帝又不能把跑道變長一點
Hey, Jorge. Come here, give me it.
嘿 豪爾赫 過來 把它給我
Come on.
加把勁
Come on, come on, come on.
上去 上 上去啊
Come on!
起飛吧
Oh! Jesus!
我的天
I've got a possible target headed due north.
有一個不明目標從北邊飛過來了
25 miles off shore.
距海岸線25英里
That's platform 14, one of Shell's helicopters.
那邊是14號平台 一架普通直升機而已
You need to disregard.
不用管
自動駕駛
美國海關
Coronamos de mi puta!
我們成功了
- Senores, salud, Barry. - Cheers, cheers.
- 好樣的 巴裏 乾杯 - 乾杯 乾杯
Esta loco este huevon.
你這傢伙真強
Esta loco.
真強
Barry,
巴裏
- esto es para ti. - Wow!
- 這是給你的 - 哇
For you.
給你的
Was that...uh, Wednesday?
你說的是星期三？
You want me to go-he wants me to go again on Wednesday.
他想讓我星期三再幹一次？
- Yes, next Wednesday. - What about the uh...
- 是的 下週三 - 那麼 呃
That runway?
我們不能在跑道上著陸嗎？
Pablo, Jorge!
豪爾赫 帕布洛
Tranquilo, tranquilo
冷靜 冷靜
Wait here, Barry. Wait here.
在這等著 巴裏
Tranquilo, tranquilo
冷靜 冷靜
Are we running?
我們是不是要逃跑？
What...
什麼情況
What is that? You want me to wait here?
什麼情況？你們要我在這等著麼？
Pablo?
帕布洛？
Oh, my God.
我的天
Si, si, si, si, si...
別別別
Barry?
巴裏？
Barry Seal?
巴裏·希爾
Schafer?
謝弗？
- Barry Seal? - Schafer?
- 巴裏·希爾？- 是你麼？
Oh, my God. You look terrible.
我的天 你看起來糟透了
So good to see you.
見到你真好
- You missing a tooth? - Yeah.
- 你掉了顆牙齒麼？- 是啊
What the fuck?
什麼情況？
- See these guys here? - Yeah.
- 你看見了那邊的幾個傢伙麼？- 嗯
I think they know that I am CIA.
我覺得他們知道我是中情局的
You're not CIA.
你不是CIA的啊
You're a drug smuggler, Barry.
巴裏 你是個毒品走私犯
Listen, Louisiana PD was notified of your arrest here.
路易斯安那警方已經知道你被捕的消息了
They're gonna raid your house at 6:00 am.
他們明早6點會去搜查你家
They're gonna pick up Lucy, bring her in for questioning.
把露西帶走 準備審問
Maybe even keep her overnight.
可能會拘留她一晚上
Oh, my God.
我的天
Oh, my God. You gotta get me out of here.
我的天 你們得把我救出去
Well, maybe...
也許
Maybe we could figure something out.
我能想點辦法
Okay. You can... you can stop now, if you want, 'cause...
如果你想的話 現在可以按暫停鍵了 因為
Believe me...
相信我
Shit gets crazy from here.
後面的事越來越瘋狂了
Remember them fellas that I told you I was takin' snaps of?
還記不記得我之前被我航拍的那些傢伙？
Turns out, they was a bunch of commies.
實際上 他們是幫共產主義分子
Called themselves Sandinistas.
稱自己為"桑地諾民族解放陣線"
These fellas managed to get their shit together
那些傢伙聚到了一起
and take control right here in this little country called Nicaragua.
試圖掌控地圖上的這個小國家 尼加拉瓜
尼加拉瓜
Oh, no, that's El Salvador. Here you go, Nicaragua.
不 這個是薩爾瓦多 這個才是尼加拉瓜
This is the first successful revolution in Central America.
這是中美洲成功的第一場革命
Now, that may have been bad news for some people.
這對某些人來說是個壞消息
But not for me. See, there's a new sheriff in town.
對我來說並不是 是這樣 鎮上來了位新鎮長
My fellow Americans, I must speak to you tonight
美國同胞們 目前美洲中部地區形勢緊張
about a mounting danger in Central America.
我今晚想同大家談談這個問題
Even after everything that happened, I-I still love Ronnie Reagan.
就算發生了那麼多事 我還是很喜歡羅尼·裏根總統
I mean, any man that can make it from that monkey movie
他以前拍了那麼多猴子主題的電影
- all the way to the White House... - What's the matter with him?
- 一路當上美國總統 - 他又哪裏不好了？
He's gotta know what the hell he's doing.
他肯定知道自己在幹什麼
What he wanted
他想把那些
was to kick them commie Sandinistas out of Nicaragua.
桑地諾共產主義分子趕出尼加拉瓜
And he wanted the Nicaraguan freedom fighters
他想讓尼加拉瓜的自由鬥士們
called Contras to do it.
也就是"反桑地諾派"完成這項事業
They need to know that the U.S. supports them
我得讓他們知道
with more than just pretty words and good wishes.
美國對他們的支持可不只是空頭支票
But Congress, well they smelled the makings of another Vietnam.
但是國會感覺到這可能會演變成另一場越南戰爭
And they outright refused to let Ronnie have his war.
他們直截了當 拒絕了總統參戰的提議
But do you think them politicians could tell the Gipper what to do?
你覺得政客會乖乖就範麼
Hell, no. He turned to the CIA.
當然不可能 他找上了中情局
And the CIA turned to me.
中情局找上了我
Schafer, Schafer, that uh, morning raid on my family...
謝弗 你說的那個清晨突襲我家的事
So, that's off now, right?
應該停止行動了吧
No, no. That's uh, that's still happening.
沒有呢 沒有停止
- What? - 6:00 am
- 你說什麼？- 還是凌晨6點展開行動
This fucking country!
這什麼鬼地方啊
- Now, hold on. - Stop!
- 慢著 - 停下啊
Now, we have a deal.
我們說好的啊
I'm not a cop, Barry.
巴裏 我不是警察
I can't make a search warrant go away, you know?
又不能隨便取消他們的搜查令
Things are in motion here.
行動已經開始了
Come on, man. What that hell am I gonna do?
那我要怎麼辦？
I suggest you get your family out of Louisiana.
我建議你把你的家人遷出路易斯安那州
- Where am I suppose to take 'em? - We got a place for you.
- 那我應該搬到哪呢？- 我們能給你們提供住處
Mena.
米納
Arkansas.
阿肯色州
Arkansas?
阿肯色州？
Hey.
嘿
Hey, Luce.
嘿 露西
- Hey, baby. - Hey.
- 親愛的 - 嘿
My God, baby, what happened to you?
我的天 親愛的 你怎麼了？
I'm okay.
我沒事
Barry, you're missing a tooth.
巴裏 你掉了顆牙齒啊
Hey, uh...
那個
We're movin'.
我們要搬家了
We gotta pack everything up.
我們得把東西打包了
We gotta be outta here before the sun comes up.
我們日出前得離開這
We uh, so we get these dresses and...
把這些衣服都
You uh, do you need all them shoes?
這些鞋子都要帶走麼？
Hey, there, sunshine.
小寶貝 你好啊
How you doin'? Now look, I'm gonna give you a plastic bag.
好久不見 現在聽我說 我給你一個塑料袋
I want you to go upstairs and put your favorite toys...
你上樓去 把你最喜歡的玩具
Go on back to bed, honey. Daddy done lost his mind.
回去睡覺吧 你爸爸瘋了
No, darlin', you listen to Daddy. You go do that.
不 聽爸爸的話
- See, we're going on an adventure. - No, we're not going on an adventure.
- 我們要去探險啦 - 不 我們不去探險
Like the time we went camping in the park?
是不是就像我們去公園露營的那次一樣？
Not actually, but... 'cause every adventure's different.
不太一樣 但是 每一次探險都是不同的
Oh, my God, you're actually serious right now.
你現在是認真的麼
Barry, it's 4:00 a.m., I'm not moving.
巴裏 現在凌晨4點啊 我才不搬家呢
- Christine's school play is tomorrow! - Do you trust me?
- 克裏斯蒂娜明天還要參加學校的演出呢 - 你信任我麼？
No!
不
But you love me. You do love me.
你愛我 你愛我的吧
Of course, I fucking love you.
我他媽的當然愛你了
Then listen, we gotta move.
那我們要搬家了
We gotta get outta here before the sun comes up.
日出前我們得離開這
米納
歡迎來到 米納 人口 2647
Look at it, they got barbecue.
看 這邊有烤肉店呢
It's got a lotta charm.
挺不錯的
This place has got a lotta charm.
這地方挺不錯的
We gots a porta potty out back and...
我們這邊又放了個移動便盆
I think that'd be cruel and unusual punishment, right?
這個懲罰真是既殘酷 又非同尋常啊
Well, I'll be sure 'n give 'em a whup for it on Monday, though.
雖然如此 我週一還是能搞定的
All right.
行吧
Thank you.
謝謝
Front door's open.
前門打開了
Shh, it's okay.
沒事的
That's an easy fix.
那玩意修起來很方便的
I gotta...
我得
Get in. Come on.
進來吧 快點
Oh, shit.
他媽的
We gotta make this quick.
你要動作快點了
She might leave me before I get back.
我回來前估計她就要走人了
So, this is all yours.
所以 這裏就歸你了
Including everything between here and your house.
從這裏到你家之間的地盤都是你的
Almost 2,000 acres.
面積達兩千畝
What do you think?
你覺得怎樣？
I own all this?
這裏都歸我了？
Oh, yeah.
是啊
This whole airport?
整個機場？
Yeah. Congratulations.
是啊 恭喜你了
AK-47s.
AK47式步槍
Soviet made for the PLO.
蘇聯為巴勒斯坦解放組織製造的
The Israelis captured these, and then secretly traded them to us.
以色列人截獲了這些武器 秘密轉手給了我們
And you're gonna fly them to Nicaragua.
你要把它們運到尼加拉瓜
Uh, you didn't say nothin' 'bout guns.
你之前可沒提過武器的事啊
It's a war, Barry.
巴裏 這是場戰爭
Freedom fighters can't put up much of a fight if they aren't armed.
有了武器 那些自由鬥士才能更有實力
This was the deal.
這是我們的約定
Or would you rather be in a Colombian prison?
還是說你想繼續在哥倫比亞的監獄裏待著？
This is every current law enforcement investigation in the Gulf Coast.
這些是目前墨西哥灣地區所有執法部門的部署情況
FBI,
包括聯調局
ATF, DEA, Customs.
煙酒火器與爆炸物管理局 緝毒局 海關
These maps will help you avoid all of 'em.
這裏的地圖能幫助你避開他們
Holy shit.
我的天
You just fly where they ain't.
按著這上面的駕駛就可以了
Everything in this hangar's mine.
機庫裏的這些都歸我了麼
Oh, yeah.
是的
That truck's mine.
那輛卡車也是我的
Mm-hmm.
嗯對
- Tools are mine. - Yes, sir.
- 工具都是我的 - 是的呢 先生
This airplane is mine.
飛機也是我的
Bag is mine.
這個包也是我的
What bag?
什麼包啊？
I fed the kids. They're sleepin'.
我餵過孩子們了 他們睡了
I unpacked the car.
我把車上的行李都打開了
That is good.
挺好的
Fixed the sink. Just the valve.
水池要修一下 就修水閥就好
See, I told you, that was gonna be easy.
看到沒 我跟你說過的 很容易的
Fuck, Barry!
去你媽的 巴裏
Okay, all right, all right. Okay.
好吧 好吧
Ima come clean.
我坦白吧
I don't work for TWA no more.
我不在航空公司上班了
No shit, Barry. Are you going to prison?
鬼扯吧你 巴裏 你是不是要進監獄了？
No, ma'am.
沒有
You gotta take care of this family.
你要照顧好這個家
'Cause I will take the kids.
要不然我就只能帶著孩子
I will go right back to working for Kentucky Fried Chicken.
回肯德基上班了
Luce, what I'm workin' on...
露西 我在做的那些事
- Barry, I'm six months pregnant. - It's top secret.
- 巴裏 我已經懷孕6個月了 - 都是機密
I need a fridge.
我要個冰箱
I need beds for our children.
我要給孩子找張床
I need a stove, a fucking washing machine.
我要個爐子 洗衣機
Washing machine over there.
洗衣機就放在那邊
Let me just...
讓我
Is this all legal?
這都是合法的麼？
All right, what I'm abou to tell you... Now, you-you...
我要告訴你的事 你 你
You gotta swear you can't ever tell anybody this, Lucy.
露西 你要發誓 不能告訴別人
All right?
可以吧？
I am working...
我在為
for the CIA.
中情局工作
反桑蒂諾派
Hola!
你們好
Howdy, amigos.
夥計們 你們好
I'm here on behalf of Uncle Sam.
我代表美國來到這裏
Look, Schafer. I ain't no military expert,
謝弗 我不是軍事方面的專家
but are you sure these are the right guys?
你確定他們靠譜麼？
'Cause they seem a damn sight more interested in my boots
因為他們好像看起來對我的靴子感興趣
than in your guns.
而不是槍
Look, this is getting big time.
馬上有大動靜了
Schafer, I just don't think I'm the guy for this.
謝弗 我是覺得我不是幹這活的合適人選
You just keep delivering that pizza, you hear me?
你只需要把貨送過去 就行了 懂了？
You just keep delivering.
送貨就行了
Hola. All right.
你們好
These are gifts.
這些是禮物
All right?
可以吧？
All right? Gifts. Regalos de mi.
好吧？是禮物 我們送給你們的
Back off. Off.
都退後 退後
Regalos.
禮物
Amigos.
各位
Atras, atras.
退後 退後
Now, these guns are gifts from Uncle Sam.
這些槍 是美國人給你們的禮物
I'm not fuckin' around.
別靠近我
Barry! Put the bat down, huevon!
巴裏 把棒球棍放下
We're all friends here.
我們是你的朋友
Jorge. What the hell are you doing here?
什麼鬼 你在這幹什麼呢？
This is Don Adolfo Calero.
這是阿道夫·卡萊
He works for your government on the revolution
他為美國政府工作
to bring down the Sandinistas.
鎮壓桑地諾解放陣線的革命
Jorge tells me you are the crazy gringo
你就是那個
who always delivers.
送貨的傢伙
We have a new business proposition to you, Barry.
我們想跟你談筆新的生意
You bring your American guns to Colombia,
你把你的槍送過來
deliver our cocaine here to the Contras,
把毒品運回去
the Contras take it by fishing boats to Miami,
通過漁船送到邁阿密
and everybody's happy.
你好我好大家好
It's for the war effort, Mr. Seal.
希爾先生 這都是為了這場戰爭
Turns out the Contras didn't really want to fight a war.
看起來這個國家並不想打仗
They just want to make money. Like the rest of us.
他們只是想賺錢而已 和我們一樣
Meanwhile, the Medellin Cartel wanted guns.
同時 那幫毒梟需要武器
So they worked out a little trade.
所以他們拿貿易做一個幌子
What was I gonna tell 'em?
我還有什麼好說的呢？
I'm just a gringo who always delivers.
我只是個送貨的
Here's how the operation worked.
具體是這麼運作的
I'd load up the guns at Mena.
我把槍從 米納運上飛機
Then, using Schafer's intel, I'd bypass any law enforcement
再利用謝弗提供的情報 繞過執法部門的監視
and fly straight to the Cartel's airstrip in Medellin.
用飛機把槍送到毒梟的地盤
Colombians, well, they love them guns.
那些哥倫比亞人可喜歡武器了
Then I'd load up with fresh powder
我從森林裏的訓練營出發
and fly on to the Contra training camp.
運輸毒品
The Contras hid the coke in fishing boats and sailed it up to Miami.
再通過漁船把貨送到邁阿密
Meanwhile, I'd get another load of powder,
與此同時 我再運一批貨
take it back to the States with a quick stop to refuel in Panama,
到巴拿馬加一次油
under the protection of my old friend, Colonel Noriega.
在那會受到我的老朋友 諾列加上校的保護
Congratulations on your promotion, General.
將軍 恭喜高昇啊
Of course, he'd get his cut too.
當然 他也能從中分成
On the way back, I'd keep an eye out for the DEA.
回去的路上我還是要小心執法人員
Then I'd dump it all in the swamps in Louisiana.
把貨空投到路易斯安那
The operation got so big, I had to get some help.
生意越做越大 我得找些幫手
Pete Dubois, manufactured guns until he discovered
皮特·杜波依斯 原來是造槍的 直到他發現
he had a knack for selling pot.
自己有獨特的販毒技巧
Stan Mason flew dope from Mexico to Arizona.
斯坦·梅森磕著藥都能把飛機從墨西哥開到亞利桑那州
Bill Cooper,
比爾·庫伯
he flew opium all around Southeast Asia during Vietnam.
越戰期間在東南亞用飛機運輸鴉片
Then there's Bob.
然後就是鮑勃
Uh, I don't know much about Bob. Hell of a pilot, though.
我對他的情況不太瞭解
I call these boys my Snowbirds.
我把他們稱作"雪鳥"飛行員
And we could fly through anything.
沒什麼飛行任務是搞不定的
Schafer.
謝弗
Barry.
巴裏
How's it going?
情況怎樣？
Hey Boss!
老大
That was fucking crazy, man!
真是太瘋狂了
How's it uh, how's it going down there?
那邊情況怎麼樣？
Oh, you know...
你懂的
Busy.
很忙
You?
你呢？
Oh, yeah.
是啊
Busy.
很忙啊
Where are they going?
他們這是要去哪呢？
We nee to borrow some of your land.
我們要借用一下你的地盤
They want you to fly 'em up here to-to train.
他們想讓你把他們用飛機接過來訓練
For training.
為了訓練
Who?
訓練誰？
The Contras.
反桑蒂諾武裝
You want me to bring 'em up here?
你要我把他們接過來？
To Mena?
送到米納來？
We're setting up a field and operational training ground.
我們設立了一個訓練基地
Where? On...
在哪呢？在
- My land? - Yeah.
- 我的土地上？- 對啊
Starting immediately.
計劃馬上開始
Which is great.
這挺好的啊
Is that a problem?
有什麼問題麼？
Uh... hey.
好吧
Whatever you need, boss.
沒問題 你們隨意
Que?
什麼？
Necesito un bano.
我們要洗澡
Uh... no bano.
呃 洗不了
Hang on! We're supposed to have 15. I'm only counting 12 here.
等下 應該有15人的 現在只有12人
Them Contras were damn excited about being in the USA.
腳踩美國大地讓反桑蒂諾派那些人欣喜若狂
They were runnin' away almost faster than we could bring 'em in.
基本上我們招的有多快 他們就溜的有多快
Hey, you two! Where do you think you're going?
嘿 那兩個 你們要去哪呢？
What, you want to quadruple the shipments?
怎麼 你想把運貨量擴大3倍？
We're counting on the Contras to win by summer if we...
如果把所需的物資提供給反桑地諾派
if we give 'em what they need.
他們估計今年夏天前就能取勝了
That's great.
挺好的
How much more can you get out of your guy in Mena?
你還能怎麼利用你那個在米納的手下？
We'll get everything out of him.
我們要讓他竭盡所能為我們服務
That's what I like to hear.
很好 我很滿意
We're expanding operations, Barry.
巴裏 我們要擴大規模
Come on. One at a time. One at a time! Hey, hold on.
別急 一個一個來 拿穩了
No, no, no.
不不不
We'll take care of everybody, just calma.
人人有份 別急
Back!
退後
Calma, calma.
冷靜啊
Everyone just calm the fuck down!
所有人都他媽的冷靜啊
Salud.
干了
- Hey, Barry. - Yeah.
- 嘿 巴裏 - 怎麼了
Do you think those Contras can win?
你覺得反桑蒂諾的那派人能贏麼？
No.
不能
Hi.
回來了呀
This just came. "Go Razorbacks, Barry."
又送福利了"衝啊 阿肯色野豬隊 巴裏贈"
Season tickets. 50-yard line.
一整個賽季的票都包了
Well, that was awful nice of him.
他人可真好啊
How much property has Seal bought us since he came to town?
他來這以後 買了多少地了？
I don't know, 500 acres?
我不太清楚 500畝吧？
2,000 acres. From the airport to Ouachita.
是2000畝 從機場一直到沃希托河
What's he want with all that worthless land?
他怎麼買得起這麼多地？
It's really none of our business. Really.
這不關我們的事
He's good people, Judy.
他是個好人 朱迪
And he's doing a lot for the community.
為社區做了很多好事
米納信託銀行
I'd like to open a bank account.
我想開個銀行賬戶
Oh, bless you!
上帝保佑
I'll be right back.
我馬上回來
David!
大衛
Come on, Christina!
加油 克裏斯蒂娜
Good job, guys.
幹得漂亮 小伙子們
- Great, Christina! - Go, go, go, go!
- 克裏斯蒂娜真棒 - 沖沖沖
Oranges. You guys want some oranges?
橘子來啦 你們想吃點嗎？
Hey guys, I got pizza!
嘿 我這有披薩
You guys want some pizza?
想吃披薩麼？
Yeah! All right. Let me just put this right...
好的 讓我放在這
There you go.
來了
- Nice wheels! - Oh, you like her?
- 這車不錯 - 你喜歡這車麼？
I do.
當然了
1982.
1982年產
All the bells and whistles.
功能齊全
First one in the State of Arkansas, and she's yours.
阿肯色州第一輛 它歸你了
She's mine?
歸我了？
She's yours.
是的
Oh, my God, Barry!
我的天啊 巴裏
Thank you!
謝謝你
- Wow. - A little somethin' extra in there.
- 哇 - 後備箱裏還有點好東西
Fuck me, Barry!
我的天啊 巴裏
What?
怎麼了？
Okay, you need to behave.
我們不要這麼張揚吧
米納
By the summer of '82,
到1982年夏季的時候
business was booming.
生意越來越紅火了
Got us at Tuesday at 3:00. Tuesday at 3:00.
週二凌晨三點送貨 週二凌晨三點送貨
We need to increase the shipments.
我們要加大運送量
Can you add a Friday delivery?
你週五能送一次嗎？
Friday? Okay. Hold on, now. Yeah?
週五嗎？行 你等等 什麼事
We want to double the amount of guns we're bringing in.
槍的運輸量要加倍
- Double? - Next pass by Friday.
- 加倍？- 週五前全部送過去
Oh, hold on, does that- does that have to be Friday?
等下 一定要週五送麼？
I opened a few front corporations.
我開了幾家空頭公司
I can't wait to learn everything there is to know
我已經迫不及待的想要瞭解
about the sign business, Mr. Seal.
您所說的業務了 希爾先生
Me too.
我也很想
I spent 30 years workin' the pumps at Gas 'n Sip.
我已經在加油站工作30年了
Well, Sir, I think it's about time you moved to upper management.
那麼先生 我覺得您是時候成為高級管理人員了
皇家酒業公司
董事長
I was takin' pictures.
我拍了很多照片
Delivering guns.
運槍
Droppin' off and pickin' up.
送貨 收錢
Damn, I was buildin' an air force.
媽的 我都快建成一個空軍了
New toy, boys.
夥計們 這是新飛機
- I wanted a scary book. - You did?
- 我想要一本恐怖故事書 - 是麼？
What are you doing Barry!
巴裏 你在幹什麼呢
Smile, Barry.
笑一個 巴裏
Jorge!
豪爾赫
Hermano.
兄弟
Lobsters!
你帶龍蝦了
Aw, you remember.
你居然還記得啊
What, do you think I'd forget?
你以為我會忘記？
Your husband is a genius.
你丈夫是個天才
When it absolutely, positively has to be delivered overnight...
當有什麼貨需要連夜運輸的時候
My wife, Lucy.
這位是我的妻子 露西
No, no, no.
不不不
I had my fingers in every pie on the rack.
我的錢存在各個地方
$10 million in Mena National.
1000萬存在米納國立銀行
$12 million in Mena State.
1200萬存在米納州立銀行
15 at Mena Trust.
1500萬存在米納信託銀行
I had 40 parked in Miami.
在邁阿密有40架飛機
20 in Panama, $7 million in lawn bags.
巴拿馬有20架 各種袋子裏裝了700萬的鈔票
8 in Samsonites, 4 buried in the woods behind my house.
8個裝滿了錢的旅行箱 其中4個埋在我家後面的樹林裏
90 pounds of gold in my closet.
衣櫥裏放了90磅的黃金
Hot damn!
我的天
Honey, watch the yoke.
親愛的 別碰到方向桿
If this ain't the greatest country in the world.
如果這不是世界上最偉大的國家
Uh...
額
JB
傑寶
Uh...
額
Yeah.
是啊
- Hey, sis! - JB!
- 嘿 姐姐 - 傑寶
What the fuck!
天哪
Look at you!
看看你
- Look at you! - God damn!
- 你看看你啊 - 上帝啊
Get in here.
進來吧
Look at this fuckin' house.
看看這房子啊
Parkin' Chevys a lot harder than it fuckin' looks, dude.
停放雪佛蘭說起來容易做起來難啊 哥們
- Hey, watch your mouth around the kids. - Sorry.
- 嘿 別說髒話 孩子在旁邊呢 - 抱歉
Is that right?
是麼？
Yeah, man.
是啊 哥們
They had me uh...
他們讓我呃
crammin' those S-10s into every goddamn inch of the parkin' lot.
把那些雪佛蘭S10都塞到停車場裏去
- Hey, you heard me. - I'm sorry!
- 嘿 剛剛我說過了 別說髒話 - 抱歉
But the thing is,
但關鍵呢
is that, the cars were so close to each other, right?
關鍵是兩輛車太接近了 就肯定會刮傷 對吧？
- you couldn't help but scratch, right? - Hmm.
- 這事誰也沒辦法 對吧？- 嗯
And then, they would take the scratches out of
然而後來 他們竟要因此
my fucking paycheck, man.
他媽的扣我工資啊 哥們
- Hey! JB. - Sorry.
- 嘿 傑寶 - 抱歉
Well, I don't know how you handled the pressure, JB.
傑寶 我真不知道你平時是怎麼減壓的
You stayin' here, you gettin' a job.
你要想待在這兒 就去找份工作
Or you know, I could just give you some folded cash,
或者呢 我乾脆給你點錢
you go and do what you want.
你愛幹嘛幹嘛去
- Don't you look at him like that. - What?
- 那絕對不行 - 怎麼？
You are gettin' a job, JB, not a handout.
你必須找份工作 別只顧伸手要錢
My brother's gettin' a job, Barry.
巴裏 讓他自己找工作
You're gettin' a job. Definitely.
你去找份工作 沒得商量
You hear that? Thats the law.
聽到了沒？你姐說的對
You gonna have to work, son.
小子 你就得找個工作
- You gonna have to work. - That's right.
- 得去工作 - 這就對了嘛
Hey, what... what is it I'll be doin' exactly?
嘿 那 那我具體要幹啥？
Yo, Barry!
呦 巴裏
Barry!
巴裏
What now, JB?
又怎麼了 傑寶？
Say, this is a big hangar. And I'm tired of sweeping.
話說啊 這飛機棚可不小 我掃累了
You can take a break when you get it done.
你什麼時候幹完 什麼時候去休息
Let's go. Get it done.
快點 把事做完
Hey man, I got a new job for ya.
嘿 小伙子 我給你個新任務
Give me a beer, man.
幫我拿瓶啤酒來
Dead soldier.
我這只剩個空酒瓶了
Eh, fuck this.
啊他媽的
Barry?
巴裏？
Yeah?
什麼事？
Roscoe dug this up in the backyard.
這是羅斯科今天從後院裏挖出來的
There are bills blowin' around everywhere.
鈔票吹得到處都是
I'll rake it up in the mornin'.
明天早晨我再收拾
I found three more of 'em up in the fireplace.
我在壁爐那邊又發現了三袋
Coronamos
勝利
Coronamos.
勝利嘍
Shit.
媽的
We had cash floodin' in from every direction.
錢從四面八方朝我們涌來
Who... who thought that was gonna be a problem? I mean...
誰 誰又能想到這還能是個問題？我是說
We were runnin' out of places to put it.
我們都沒地兒放錢了
Easy. Whoa.
喔 慢點
Don't get behind him. These are dangerous animals.
站遠點 這些馬很危險
You know, maybe we should call the trainer.
我說啊 或許我們應該叫馴馬師來
No, honey, I got this.
不用 親愛的 我能搞定的
Come on. Hang on.
快點 撐住
JB got a new car.
傑寶買了輛新車啊
Did you give that boy a raise?
你多給了他錢？
Hey, Barry, Luce.
嗨 巴裏 露絲
What in the holy fuck? That girl is 15.
我的天 那女孩只有15歲吧
- It's huge. - I told you it's huge.
- 這地方真大啊 - 我跟你說過的
- You actually live here? - Uh-huh.
- 你真的住在這麼？- 是啊
Hey. Can you talk to you for a second?
嘿 我能跟你說幾句麼？
Yeah.
可以啊
- What? - Come here
- 什麼情況？- 過來
- What the hell, JB? - What?
- 你這是搞什麼鬼 傑寶？- 什麼？
- I hadn't done nothin' yet. - JB.
- 我又沒做什麼錯事 - 傑寶
- JB. Come on. - Hi, Mrs. Seal.
- 傑寶 過來 - 您好 希爾夫人
What... we was just gonna go for a swim.
怎麼了 我只是準備去跟她游泳而已
Come here.
過來
- Please don't tell my mama I was here. - Come on.
- 求求你別告訴我媽我在這裏 - 快過來
Where'd you get the money for this car?
你買這車的錢從哪來的？
Ima be honest with you, Barry. 'Cause I can't lie to you.
我就跟你說實話了 巴裏 因為我沒法對你撒謊
I stole it from the hangar.
我從機庫那偷的
What?
行啊你？
I opened up one of the Samsonites.
我打開了其中一個新秀麗背包
I found so much fuckin' money in there.
找到了他媽的好多錢
- So much goddamn money. - JB, JB, JB...
- 錢真他媽的多啊 - 傑寶 傑寶啊
JB, you can't do that.
傑寶 你不能這麼做
500 down to 300. Watch out for that tree at the end.
500英尺下降至300英尺 小心別碰到降落點處的樹
Yeah, I remember that.
嗯 我知道
Hell, Pete, you gotta turn that off. I can't see nothin' with that on.
我去 皮特 你得把手電關了 我什麼也看不清了
Gotcha.
好的
75. 50.
75英尺 50英尺
Nicely done, boss.
幹得漂亮 老闆
You boys see this?
你們看見了嗎
Ho! God!
我了個擦
緝毒局
You are in violation of the air defense identification zone.
你們現已侵入防空識別區
We are ordering you to land immediately.
我們命你立即著陸
Follow us to New Orleans NAS.
跟我們到新奧爾良海軍航空站降落
All right, boys. Gonna be a long night.
準備好 兄弟們 今晚可有我們折騰的了
Come back to the sea, 105 knots. And flaps down.
現在調頭向外海面飛 時速105海里 左翼向下
I repeat, we are ordering you to land immediately.
重複一次 我們命你立即著陸
The DEA was using these fancy new jets
美國緝毒局現在用的是最新式飛機
that we couldn't outrun.
我們的飛機速度可趕不上他們的
Follow to New Orleans NAS.
跟我們到新奧爾良海軍航空站降落
But all that speed comes at a heavy price.
不過他們飛這麼快可是在燒錢啊
I repeat...
我重複
They could go fast.
他們可以飛得很快
But we could go slow.
可我們卻可以飛得很慢
For a long time
而且耐力久的很
Low fuel.
燃油將盡
We gotta turn around, guys. We're bingo.
我們必須返航 不能再跟了
Those pricks are right fucking there.
那幫混蛋就在我們眼前
All right, boys.
好啦 兄弟們
DEA finally ran out of gas. Time to head home.
緝毒局那幫貨終於沒油了 我們可以回家了
Bill! What the fuck, man?
比爾 你他媽幹啥呢
Where you headed, buddy? Come on.
你要去哪啊 哥們兒 跟上啊
All right, I'll get him. I'll get him.
沒事 我去跟他 我去
Bill! Come on, turn around. Come on, let's go.
比爾 來啊 調頭啊 來啊 回家了
Bill? You hearin' me?
比爾 你聾了嗎
Oh, son of a bitch!
哦 這個王八蛋
Bill's asleep.
比爾睡著了
God damn!
我擦了
Bill, wa-wake up, man!
比爾 醒醒 哥們兒
That motherfucker can sleep anywhere.
這傻屌在哪都能睡得著
Wake up, Bill.
快醒醒 比爾
Bill!
比爾
- Good morning, Bill! - Okay, I'm up.
- 早上好啊 比爾 - 好啦 我醒了
Welcome back.
你可算醒了
聯邦調查局
銀行監管部
Those bank financials that you asked for.
這是你要的銀行財務記錄
Yeah.
好的
There's a lot of money in Mena, Arkansas.
有不少錢都送到阿肯色州的米納銀行了啊
Thanks.
謝謝了
I think you're gonna appreciate what we've done here, Barry.
我想你看到我們的工作後會覺著很不錯的 巴裏
Making me my own vault?
給我自己造金庫呢？
Oh, no, no. We're using this auxiliary for all our other customers.
並不是 這個分庫是我們準備給其他客戶的
We gave you the main vault.
我們給你的是主庫
How 'bout that.
這個可以有
阿肯色州土地投資銀行
米納州立銀行
阿肯色州
商業銀行
Aerostar 2-1-9-3-Gold.
航空之星2193G號飛機
Head to New Orleans Naval Air Station at once.
立即飛往新奧爾良海軍航空站
Yeah, come on, come on, come on!
好呀 來呀 你來呀
You better run, you prick.
我他媽讓你跑 別讓我追到你
This is the United States Border Patrol.
我們是邊境巡邏隊
Shit.
倒霉
We are ordering you to land.
我們命你著陸
Hey, boys.
行啊 哥們
I see you finally got smart and got a slower plane.
看來你們終於開竅了啊 弄來了個飛得慢的飛機
Two of 'em.
還是兩架
That's right, son.
對啊 小子
We're up here as long as you want.
我們今天跟你玩個夠
Aerostar, we are ordering you to land immediately.
航空之星 我們命你立即著陸
All right, motherfuckers. Let's land.
行 你們這群混蛋 著陸就著陸
I repeat, we are ordering you to land imm...
我重複一次 我們命你立即著陸
What the fuck?
他他媽要幹什麼？
Stay on him.
跟住他
Shit.
操
Oh, shit!
我操
Is this your yard?
這是你家的院子嗎？
That's for the damage. And uh...
這是給你的賠償 還有
Here's a little somethin' extra for your sister.
這些給你的妹妹
Hey, little darlin'.
嗨 小可愛
And your bike.
自行車我買了
You never saw me.
你從沒見過我
A plane crashed in Louisiana
一架飛機在路易桑那州墜毀
with 200 kilos of Colombian powder.
載有200公斤的哥倫比亞毒品
200.
200喲
- Right. - Is that your boy?
－ 是啊 － 是你要抓的那個嗎？
I'm sorry, are you working for the fucking DEA now?
問你個事 你他媽什麼時候成緝毒警的？
Interesting read.
有趣的報道
I got it.
我拿走了
- Hello, amigo. - Si.
- 你好 哥們 - 嗯
I had to get out of Colombia in the middle of the night.
我今晚必須逃出哥倫比亞
I wasn't the only one having trouble with the DEA.
緝毒局盯上的倒霉蛋兒可不只我一個
Escobar's gone crazy and declared war on the government.
艾斯科巴瘋了 他向政府宣戰了
Thanks to Pablo Escobar's unique management style...
由於帕布洛 艾斯科巴的獨到管理風格
the cartel found themselves kicked out of Colombia.
整個販毒集團在哥倫比亞毫無立足之地
The only place the DEA couldn't touch him?
你想知道哪還有他容身之處？
That's right. Nicaragua.
對了 也就剩下尼加拉瓜了
尼加拉瓜
- Is everything okay here? - Yes, we're late.
- 都準備好了麼？- 是的 我們已經晚了
We're going to meet Sr. Vaughan.
我們是去見沃恩先生
He's the Minister of Interiors.
他是內政部的官員
Controls the airstrips.
他負責的是機場報道
It's how we get you in.
用他的關係能保你進機場
Barry, sit and shut your mouth.
巴裏 坐在這什麼也別說
我愛人令我自豪
My baby makes me proud
上帝啊 她是多麼讓我引以為傲
Lord, don't she make me proud
她從不耍脾氣
She never makes a scene
一直緊緊地依附於我
By hangin' all over me
- Here's your butter, sir. - Thank you.
- 先生 這是你要的黃油 - 謝謝
因為人們就是愛閒扯
'Cause people like to talk
上帝啊 他們真的很喜歡閒扯
Lord, don't they love to talk
但是當他們熄滅等燈火
But when they turn out the lights
我知道她一定會隨我離去
I know she'll be leavin' with me
當我們回家之後
And when we get behind closed doors
她鬆開滿頭長髮
Then she lets her hair hang down
What's up?
你好警官
How you doin'?
你好啊
她讓我體會到做男人的樂趣
And she makes me glad that I'm a man
Stop runnin'!
站住
Fuck!
操
Sorry, it's my wife.
對不起 是我的妻子呼我
- Hey Luce, you hear me? - Yes.
- 露西 你聽得清嗎？- 是的
- Honey? You all right? - Yeah, I can hear you.
- 親愛的？你還好嗎？- 是的 我聽得到你
Honey, I hate to tell you this right now, but JB's been arrested.
親愛的 我有個不好的消息 傑寶被捕了
- That little shit. - What happened?
- 這個傻逼 - 怎麼回事
I don't know. He got caught with a lot of money.
我不太清楚 他被抓的時候正拎著一箱子錢
- That dumbfuck. - Honey...
- 這個傻逼 - 親愛的
What do you want me to do here, babe?
你想我在這做什麼 寶貝？
There ain't nothin' to do, really.
什麼也不做 真的
Uh, I'm just in a meeting.
呃 我這兒正開會呢
And we'll go over that when I get home.
等我回家再解決這件事
All right? I got... I'll take care of that.
好嗎？我有我會想辦法解決的
- All right? - All right, hurry up, Barry.
- 好嗎？- 好的 快回來吧 巴裏
You just sit tight. I love you.
你坐等我回家就好 我愛你
How much? Cuanto?
多少錢？多少錢？
"Mil quin..." that's 15 uh...
1500公斤 那是1500呃
1500 kilos, Barry.
1500公斤 巴裏
1500?
1500公斤？
Si. In one go.
對 一趟送完
In one go?
一趟送完？
Si.
是的
Well, we ain't never done that before.
這個 我們以前沒這麼幹過
Sanctuary isn't cheap.
想呆在這避難就得是這個價
That's a lot
這可不少
Can you do it?
你能做到嗎？
Yeah, I'm gonna get home...
能 我得先回到家
Right now. I'm gonna leave. Then uh, we'll figure it out.
現在我就得離開這 之後我們會想辦法搞定的
I'll figure it out.
我自己會搞定
Get it fucking done.
你最好能搞定
Fucking lawyer doesn't know shit.
這狗屁律師什麼也不懂
I got two fucking priors, man. And he doesn't understand.
我可是有兩次前科的啊 大哥 那律師就是不明白
No, no, no. He does understand.
不不不 他很明白
And you gotta do what he tells you to do.
你必須按照他要求的去做
No, he doesn't, man.
不 他不明白 大哥
One more strike, man. One more strike and I can go to prison...
我再被定罪一次 大哥 再多一次我就得進監獄了
- for-for life, man.
- 終生監禁啊 老大 - 傑寶
JB, just... hold on.
傑寶 你先別掛電話
Barry? Barry, are you there?
巴裏？巴裏 你還在聽嗎？
Daddy!
老爸
Hey, darlin'.
嗨 小天使
What's that? Hold on.
那是什麼？稍等
- Yeah? - Barry.
- 你是？- 巴裏
We've been trying to get a hold of you, amigo.
我們一直在聯繫你啊 哥們
Yeah, I know that, amigo. Listen, could you hold on, I'll be right back.
是的 我知道的 哥們 聽著 你稍等我一下 我馬上回來
- JB? - Yeah.
- 傑寶？- 我在
There's some people that wanna talk to me.
有人想跟我談談
No, no no. You don't talk to anyone about anything.
不不不 跟誰你也別多說話
Now, you do what that lawyer tells you to.
現在 你就按照律師要求的去做
And you keep your fucking mouth shut.
把你的鳥嘴給我管住了
- I'm taking care of this. - Okay.
- 我會搞定一切的 - 好的
Listen, Jorge, we gotta put on the brakes for a bit.
聽著 豪爾赫 我們那事兒得往後延一段時間了
Brakes? No, no, no. No brakes.
後延？不不不 不能後延
We have product to move.
我們必須出貨了
I understand amigo, but I-I got a family situation.
我明白 哥們 但我家這邊出了點小狀況
Eh, your brother-in-law. We know all about it.
我知道 你小舅子嘛 他的事我們都瞭解
- We'll handle it, amigo. - No, no, no, no.
- 我們會解決的 哥們 - 不不 不用
- I don't want you to handle it. - Barry, listen.
- 我不想你們插手這件事 - 巴裏 聽著
- I got it. I got this. - Barry, listen to me.
- 我能解決 我可以的 - 巴裏 你聽我說
We'll handle it, okay? So don't worry.
我們會解決的 好吧？你什麼也不用擔心
- We'll talk business later. - Jorge...
- 生意的事我們之後再談 - 豪爾赫
Barry, they don-they don't know about them suitcases you got.
巴裏 他們不 他們什麼都不知道 你的那些箱子
or what you got in them planes, the guns you got.
你飛機裏運的什麼 你的那些槍
They don't know anything about it.
他們對這些毫不知情
We're good, man.
我們安全了 大哥
I can't fix this. You hear?
這事我處理不了了 你聽見了嗎？
They're gonna give you 10- 10 years for not talkin'.
你什麼也不說 他們會判你10年
That's 10 years people gotta worry you will.
這10年那幫人會一直擔心你會
I didn't say anything, man.
我什麼也沒說 大哥
You can talk to the goddamn lawyer.
你可以跟那律師說啊
Where we going, man?
我們這是要去哪
You serious? I'm fucking family.
你是認真的麼？我可是你的親人啊
We're family!
我們是親人啊
That's right. Right. We're a family.
你說的對 我們是親人
- What's that? - Inside's a passport...
- 這是什麼？- 裏面有護照
first-class ticket to Bora Bora and enough cash...
飛往大溪地博拉博拉島的頭等艙機票和足夠的現金
Enough cash to make a damn good life for yourself.
這些錢夠你他媽自己活一輩子的了
Now, you're gonna get in that car,
現在 你上那輛車
and you're gonna drive straight to Dallas Fort Worth Airport
你開車直奔達拉斯沃爾斯堡機場
and nowhere else.
哪也別去
You don't even stop to take a piss.
想撒尿你也給我憋住
- You hear me? - Yeah, I hear you.
- 你聽懂我的意思了嗎？- 是的 我懂了
Good luck, kid.
祝你好運吧 小子
I'll tell you what, Barry.
你給我聽好了 巴裏
I'm gonna send you a goddamn address, okay, Barry?
我會把地址郵給你 明白嗎 巴裏
You're gonna start sending me cash on the fucking regular.
你必須定時給我送錢
You understand? You hear me?
你聽懂了嗎？我說的夠明白了吧？
Oh, and Barry...
啊 對了 巴裏
Fuck you, man! Fuck you and my cunt sister!
操你媽的 你和我的賤逼姐姐都去死吧
Hey!
嘿
Money every week, asshole!
每周給我送錢 混蛋
What the fuck?
這他媽
What? Oh, shit.
這 我操了
Hey, hey! Barry!
嘿 巴裏
Hey, Barry!
Barry!
巴裏
Yeah, Bill, what do you need? What do you need?
怎麼了 比爾 你想怎麼樣？你想怎麼樣？
Man, man, I'm like freakin' out, man.
哥們 我現在心裏慌的很
Man, what is goin' on with JB?
傑寶現在怎麼樣了
- Huh? - Don't worry about JB.
- 說啊？- 你不用操心傑寶
What if he talks, man?
要是他繃不住把我們賣了呢？
- He ain't gonna. - Yeah, but what if he does?
- 他不會的 - 可要是他挺不住了呢？
- He ain't gonna talk, Bill. - How do you know?
- 比爾 他不會出賣我們的 - 你怎麼知道的
I am fucking positive.
我就是知道
Okay, man.
好吧 哥們
Good, I'm gonna trust you on this one, man.
好吧 你這麼說我就信你吧
Good.
好
In a calendar year, your operations have transported
在一個自然年裏 你給
10,500 Russian AKs to the Contras.
反桑地諾軍運送了10500把俄羅斯AK47式步槍
Yeah.
是的
5,000 of which, have found themselves in the hands
其中5000把槍 卻是在哥倫比亞販毒集團
of the Colombian Cartel.
的人手裏
- Right, but... - Out of the 916 Contras
- 是的 但是 - 在916名被帶往
brought in to the United States to train,
美國訓練的反抗軍當中
only half made it back to Nicaragua.
只有一半的人成功返回到了尼加拉瓜
- Half is... - The other half are in the wild...
- 另一半 - 另一半的人現在去向歸屬不明
What's going on here?
這裏發生了什麼？
Oh, deaf. We had to send the Contras home.
啊 剛才沒聽見 我們必須把這些反抗軍送回家
- Home? - Yeah.
- 送回家？- 是啊
They weren't fighting.
他們可沒去參戰
That's the reality of that situation.
現在情況就是這樣
You know, it didn't help that their guns were in Colombia.
你懂的 我們的槍在哥倫比亞 對他們一點幫助都沒有
Did it, Barry?
是吧 巴裏
So...
那
What now?
現在幹什麼？
We'll call you.
我們會給你打電話
Call me? Schafer?
給我打電話？謝弗
Hey, Schafer.
嘿 謝弗
Who the fuck's Schafer?
誰他媽是謝弗
Okay, everybody. You know the drill.
大家注意 你們知道流程的
Everybody gets a burn bag.
所有人拿一個焚燒袋
Into it, you put anything with Barry Seal's face
把你們手裏所有帶有巴裏·希爾照片
or name on it.
或者名字的資料都放進去
Come on, boys. We gotta move.
來吧 兄弟們 我們得撤了
We gotta get all this stuff outta here.
我們得把所有的東西都帶走
Pete. What, everything?
皮特 你什麼意思 全都帶走？
Come on, boys, lets go.
快點 哥們 趕緊開始收拾
We gotta move this out. Let's go! Let's go!
我們得把東西都帶走 動起來
Into the burn bag, go!
都放進焚燒袋裏 快
Purchase orders, aircraft invoices,
訂購單 機票收據
Need a team here, let's move it out.
我這需要來幾個人 把東西都挪走
Oh, shit, man. Look at all these guns.
我了個擦 怎麼有這麼多槍
We gotta move all of it.
我們得把他們都挪走
Where are we supposed to put all this stuff?
我們能把他們挪到哪去？
Just get it off my property.
別在我這就行
Anything with the words "Mena".
所有跟米納有關的資料
Fuel bills, memos, names, directives, photos, anything like that,
加油票 備忘錄 名字 指令材料 照片 所有類似的東西
anything that can link us with him,
所有能把我們跟他聯繫在一起的東西
you put in the burn bag...
你都放進焚燒袋裏
and then what do you do with it?
然後你們怎麼處理這些材料？
- Burn it. - You burn it.
- 燒了它 - 對 你都給它燒光了
Bob, I need a little help back here.
鮑勃 我這需要點幫助
- Gimme a hand with this shit. - You got it.
- 你過來幫我一下 - 沒問題
Seal! DEA! Back away from the truck, with your hands in the air.
希爾 我們是美國緝毒局 從卡車那後退 舉起你的雙手
Drop the fucking box, shithead.
把那箱子給我放下 你個混蛋
Put up your hands! Nice and high.
舉起雙手 給我舉高舉好了
- ATF! Drop your weapons! - What the fuck?
- 我們是煙草酒精火器管理局的 放下武器 - 什麼情況？
- Whoa, whoa, whoa! DEA! - Lower your guns!
- 喔 喔 別緊張 我們是美國緝毒局 - 把武器放下
Put your freaking guns down!
你們都他媽放下武器
- Everybody's friends here! - It's cool.
- 我們都是兄弟部門 - 別緊張
- DEA, all right? - This is our collar.
- 我們是美國緝毒局 好吧？- 這是我們的警徽
- Bullshit. - No, no, no, no.
- 少他媽放屁 - 不不不
State Police!
州警察
What the fuck are ya'll doin' in my county?
你們在我地盤上干他媽啥呢？
Nobody move!
都別動
FBI!
美國聯邦調查局
Well, hey, boys. How about my phone call?
那個 各位 我能打個電話嗎？
We're sorry, you have reached a number that has been disconnected
很抱歉 你撥打的電話無法接通
- or is no longer in service. - Bullshit.
- 或者已停止服務 - 他媽的
If you feel you have reached this recording in error...
如果你覺著我們呢這邊記錄有誤
Come on, Seal.
來吧 希爾
You know who I am, Mr. Seal?
你知道我是誰吧 希爾先生
- No, ma'am - I'm Dana Sibota.
- 不 我不認識你 - 我叫戴娜·希伯塔
State Attorney General.
州檢察長
You've got DEA, ATF, FBI all wantin' their pound of flesh.
緝毒局 酒煙火管理局 聯邦調查局得都想抓你
Yes, ma'am, its... It's quite a room.
是啊 這屋子的陣容可真強大
Yeah. Well, you hit the trifecta, didn't ya?
是啊 你這是連中三彩了啊 是吧？
I mean, guns, drugs, money launderin'.
我是說違禁槍支 販毒 洗錢
And the State of Arkansas,
而阿肯色州政府
is gonna rip the bark right off o' you, boy.
想把你撕個粉碎 小子
We are gonna put you in a 4X6 cell for the rest of your life.
我們會把你丟進24平的小黑屋享受終生監禁待遇
- Ma'am, that's a long time. - Yeah.
- 女士 這可不短啊 - 你說對了
Miss Sibota, I have Governor Clinton on the line.
希伯塔女士 克林頓州長來電話了
He says it's urgent.
他說很緊急
It's...the Governor.
這可是州長
It's the Governor.
這可是州長啊
Put him through. Clear the room. Take him with you.
電話接進來吧 屋裏人都撤了吧 把他帶走
Yeah? What do you need, Bill?
有何貴幹 比爾？
Did you all know
你們知道嗎？
that Caddies have more trunk space
凱迪拉克後備箱的空間
than any other car in the world?
比全世界所有車的後備箱都大
I'll give each and everyone of you a Caddy.
我會給你們每一個人一輛凱迪拉克
- Huh? - You'd do that for all of us?
- 是嗎？- 你會給我們每人一輛？
Yes, sir, I would.
是的 先生 我會的
I'd get all ya'll Caddies. Have 'em here this afternoon.
我會給你們每人一輛凱迪拉克 今天下午就能到位
What're you tryin' to do, Seal? Add another 20 for bribery?
你現在的行為只會給你自己加一條賄賂罪另判20年徒刑
Oh, no, no, no. I'm just offerin' you Caddies for your troubles.
哦不 不要誤會 我給你們車是因為給你們添了不少麻煩
What trouble, Seal?
什麼麻煩 希爾？
Well, bringing me down here, for one.
把我抓到這 這是其一
See, Ima walk outta here.
知道麼 我會從這清白的走出去
Ima walk outta here.
清白的走出去
And there ain't a damn thing any one o' you can do about it.
你們誰也阻止不了我
Okay.
好吧
Do it.
開鎖吧
- Wait, wait, wait a minute. - No, no, no.
- 等等 等一下 - 別說話了都
- He's free to go, boys. - What the fuck?
- 各位 他可以走了 - 這他媽是怎麼回事？
What the hell do you mean, "He's free to go"?
他可以走了？你這話是什麼意思？
You wanna explain what's goin' on here?
你能解釋這是怎麼回事麼？
- He's free to go. - Free to go?
- 他可以走了 - 他可以走？
You boys shoulda taken the Caddies.
讓你們不要車 現在過這村沒這店嘍
I'll be seein' you, Seal.
我會一直盯著你的 希爾
Ma'am.
好的 女士
I tell ya,
我得說
It is good to see you boys, I ain't gonna lie.
看到你們真好 我講心裏話
But I figured you would have to show up, see.
其實我早就猜到你們必須來幫我脫困的 知道吧
I just know too much.
我知道的太多了
Schafer sent you, right?
謝弗派你來的 對吧？
Who the fuck is Schafer?
誰他媽認識謝弗？
All right, all right now. Seriously, fellas, who are you?
好啦 不開玩笑 哥幾個 你們到底是誰
還記得那次？
What about the time?
你在空翻
You were rollin' over
結果臉著地了
Fall on your face
那時候你肯定很快樂
You must be having fun
Usually, I talk with you from my office in the West Wing of the White House, but...
平時呢 我都是在白宮西廂的我的辦公室跟你對話 不過
tonight, there's something special to talk about.
今晚的談話內容有些特殊
And I've asked someone very special to join me.
我也邀請了特別嘉賓
下後劃 你還好嗎？
Backslidin' How do you do?
Are we going...
我們這是去
這些狡猾的人
These slippery people
會把你看透
Gonna see you through
Nancy...
南希
Not long ago, I was asked by a group of children what to do
不久前 有一群孩子問我如果有人向他們出售毒品
if they were offered drugs.
該怎麼做
And I answered, "Just say no".
而我回答說 就跟他們說不買
Drug criminals are ingenious.
毒販們都特別精
So we must be smarter and stronger and tougher than they are.
所以我們必須比他們更聰明 更強壯 更堅強
Say yes to your life.
應嚮往光明的人生
And when it comes to drugs and alcohol...
而面對毒品和酒精
just say no.
請止步
You a pilot?
你是個飛行員？
- I've been known to fly some. - Me too.
- 我對駕駛飛機並不陌生 - 我也是
Air National Guard. '68 to '69.
空中國民警衛隊 68年和69年服役
Junior?
到你了
Well, see you around, flyboy.
那 我們回見吧 飛行員
All right.
好的
上帝救救我們吧
God help us
幫我們丟棄理智
Help us lose our minds
The Sandinistas are burning
桑地諾的支持者在大街上
the American flag in the streets.
燒我們的國旗
Please. There is no deal if we don't get the Sandinistas.
如果我們搞不定桑地諾的人 就沒戲
- Then there's no deal. - Horseshit.
- 那沒戲就沒戲 - 放屁
There's no deal unless we get Medellin.
我們拿不下麥德林販毒集團才是真沒戲了
Now, you may be wondering why my ass wasn't in jail at this point.
現在你可能在想都這個時候了 為什麼我還沒進監獄？
This is disgusting!
這簡直不忍直視
Now, I gotta be honest. Frankly, so was I.
我不跟你們撒謊 其實我也想知道
This fella here, is with the DEA.
這哥們呢 是美國緝毒局的
And this fella here, is a colonel named Ollie North.
而這位呢 是個叫奧利·諾斯的上校
Reagan's go-to guy.
裏根總統團隊的關鍵人物
The DEA just wants to nail the Medellin Cartel once and for all.
美國緝毒局想一次搞定麥德林販毒集團永絕後患
Now, at the same time, Colonel North wants to prove
與此同時呢 諾斯上校想證明
that commies in Central America are involved in the drug trade.
美國中部的販毒行當裏有共產黨在插手
- Let me say that again, - This is disgusting!
- 我再說一次 - 這簡直不忍直視
Colonel North wants to prove
諾斯上校想證明
that commies are dealing drugs.
共產黨在美國販毒
And why am I in the room?
而為什麼把我帶到這間屋子裏呢？
'Cause I'm the gringo who always delivers.
因為我經手的販毒行動就沒失敗過
So you want me to keep going?
所以呢你想讓我重操舊業？
For your country.
為了你的國家
We're gonna bring these guys down.
我們一起把他們連根拔起
And you're gonna be a hero.
而你將成為一名英雄
All right then.
那好吧
They put me right back in business.
我又干回老本行了
Now, I'm working for the White House.
現在我是為白宮工作了
白宮
All right you have three cameras.
你們現在有3個相機
50-picture loads each.
每個能拍50張照片
You have one here in a bag.
袋子那兒有一個照相機
The sightline goes straight down the back
照相方向向下直對著飛機後部
to where those two gentlemen are now.
就是那兩位先生現在的位置
You have two more cameras above each door.
另外兩個相機會放在每個門的上方
Sightlines directly in front of the door.
照相方向直對著門
Each camera has a cord.
每個相機都有繩索固定
You just press this button to take a picture.
按下這個按鈕就能拍照
That's it.
就這麼簡單
Let's go.
我們撤
I can see the cords, Barry.
我能看到固定繩 巴裏
Yeah.
是啊
I can see this damn cord
連我都能看的到這繩索
which means they're gonna be able to see it.
他們自然也能看得見
- We'll hide it. - I'm not a photographer.
- 我們得把它們藏好 - 我不是攝像師
- Your thumb work? - Yeah.
- 你大拇指能動嗎？- 能啊
Well, you just push a button.
那你就按那個按鈕唄
When am I supposed to press the button?
那我該什麼時候按這個按鈕呢？
When the guys are standin' here holdin' the powder.
當他們站在這手拿著毒品的時候
You know what, fuck it, Pete. I'll take the pictures.
行了 不用你了 照片我自己來拍
Fuck.
媽的
Listen, once we have one of these photos,
聽好 一旦照片到手
who exactly is gonna be lookin' at 'em?
會是由誰來去看這些照片嗎？
These photos are gonna be on a need-to-know basis.
這些照片 有權限看到他們的人都能看到
Need-to-know.
有權限
They're gonna be classified at the highest levels, Barry.
他們會被列為最高機密 巴裏
- Daddy! - Classified.
- 爸爸 - 列為機密
We do recognize the dangers involved here.
我們知道這很危險
No, you don't.
不 你們不知道
Or you can always tell us to fuck off
那你也可以讓我們捲鋪蓋滾蛋
and spend the next 30 years in Leavenworth.
然後自己在監獄裏呆30年
Come on Boss! Let's get this over with!
來吧 老大 我們一起搞定這件事
I'll see you, Rangel.
回頭見 蘭格爾
- Smile, Barry! - Bye, Daddy!
- 笑一個 巴裏 - 爸爸 再見
Shit, there's a fuckin' army up there.
我操 外面可是一整支軍隊啊
They're gonna torture us.
他們肯定會折磨我們
Pull our tongues out through our necks.
把舌頭從我們的嘴裏拽出來
That ain't helpin', Pete.
說這些屁用沒有 皮特
They gonna cut us up in little pieces.
他們會把我們剁成一片一片的
Feed us to the pigs. I won't be fed in no pigs, Barry.
然後用我們的碎肉餵豬 我可不想被拿去餵豬 巴裏
We gotta keep our shit together. Hola!
我們得打起十二萬分精神 你們好
We're gettin' yayo.
我們給他們可卡因
Take these damn pictures, and get the hell outta here.
拍下些該死的照片 之後我們就馬上離開這
Keep our shit together.
打起精神來
Raise your hand!
舉起手來
Fuck.
媽的
Hello. No, no, no.
嗨 別開槍
Amigos!
哥們兒們
They're gonna hear that goddamn camera, Barry.
他們鐵定能發現那幾個該死的相機的 巴裏
Amigos.
哥們兒們
Escobar, Ochoa.
艾斯科巴 奧喬亞
Raise your hand!
舉起手來
Hey, hola.
嘿 你們好
Amigo. Que paso?
哥們 你還好麼
What's this?
這是什麼
Regalos para Escobar y Ochoa.
這些是送你給你的禮物 艾斯科巴 奧喬亞
Hey, Jorge!
嘿 豪爾赫
Jorge, fuck.
豪爾赫 這他媽
Come on, man.
拜託啦 哥們
A little help.
幫幫忙
Shoot the gringos.
開槍打這幫外國佬
What?
什麼？
Shoot the gringos.
開槍打他們
- What'd you say? - Shoot the gringos!
- 你說什麼？- 開槍打死他們
Shoot the gringos!
開槍打死他們
No, no, no, no.
停 停手
No.
別開槍
You fucker.
你個混蛋
Bad for crazy gringos.
嚇死你們倆了吧
Ochoa!
奧喬亞
What the fuck is this, Ochoa?
這他媽是什麼 奧喬亞
Stand the fuck up.
站起來
Hey, you're shaking. You're shaking.
哈 你都發抖了 你都發抖了
Look at this.
快看啊
Hey, he pissed himself, man.
哈 他都嚇尿了
You got me. That was a good one.
確實嚇到我了 確實被你騙到了
That was a good one.
被你騙到了
I saved your life, Barry.
我救了你一命啊 巴裏
- I saved your life, eh. - Yes, you did.
- 我救了你一命啊 - 沒錯
- Remember that. - Yeah.
- 你記住了啊 - 嗯
Remember. Crazy gringo.
記住了 外國佬
Come here, Barry.
過來 巴裏
Hey, Jorge.
嘿 豪爾赫
Now, let's go say hi to Pablo.
來 我帶你去見帕布洛
Pablo's here?
帕布洛也來了？
Si. He's paranoid, amigo. On edge.
是啊 他現在猜疑心重極了 哥們 馬上就要炸了
Thinks everyone is out to get him.
他總以為有人想害他
Hola, Pablo!
你好 帕布洛
Let's do it
我們這就交易吧
Are we good?
沒問題吧？
What?
什麼？
Are we good?
我說沒問題吧？
Are we good, Barry?
是不是沒問題 嗯？巴裏
Si... Si.
是的 是的
Estoy aqui.
我就在這裏
Y traje tus Harleys.
衣服跟哈雷摩托挺配的啊
Ah, okay.
啊 是很好
So? We're still friends?
所以呢？我們還是朋友吧？
That was a good one
剛才你真騙到我了
that you pulled right there. You really got me.
就你剛才那個 確實給我耍了
This dude.
這傢伙
Hey, you know, I'm gonna have to get you back.
告訴你 我早晚也會給你整這麼一出
What's he saying?
他說啥呢？
He's gonna get us back on that joke, Pablo.
他說他也要涮我們一次 巴勃羅
- Oh, yeah? - Yeah!
- 是嗎？- 是啊
Jorge...
豪爾赫
Look at this, my friend.
哥們 好好看看吧
Say cheese, motherfuckers.
說"茄子" 蠢蛋們
We're gonna make history.
我們會創造歷史的
Barry Seal!
巴裏·希爾
Barry Seal... He's a goddamn genius.
巴裏·希爾 你他媽就是個天才
- Yay! - Yay!
- 耶 - 耶
There seems to be no crime
桑地諾的支持者們
to which the Sandinistas will not stoop.
幾乎就是無惡不作
This is an outlaw regime.
這就是個非法政權
The Sandinistas have even involved themselves
桑地諾的支持者們甚至
in the international drug trade.
參與了國際販毒貿易
I know every American parent
我知道全美所有關注毒品問題的
concerned about the drug problem will be outraged
父母在得知尼加拉瓜政府官員深入參與到
to learn that top Nicaraguan government officials
毒品走私的罪行當中之後
are deeply involved in drug trafficking.
一定會極度憤慨
This picture, secretly taken at a military airfield
從這張在馬那瓜城外的軍隊機場
outside Managua,
秘密拍攝到的照片當中
shows Federico Vaughan, a top aide to one of
我們可以看到費德裏科·沃恩
the nine comandantes who rule Nicaragua...
共九位指揮官統治尼加拉瓜 他是其中一位高級副官
Fuck!
操
loading an aircraft with illegal narcotics
正在往一架飛機上裝載非法毒品
Motherfuckers! That's your fucking face, Barry!
這幫混蛋 那可是你的臉啊 巴裏
This is an outlaw regime.
這是個非法政權
Oh, my God.
我的天啊
Just as you said, Pablo.
就如你之前所料 帕布洛
That son of a bitch.
那個王八蛋
Pablo, we must face it immediately.
帕布洛 我們必須立即解決這個問題
- Go on. - Yes, sir.
- 繼續 - 遵命
I am truly sorry, Barry. North jumped the gun.
我非常抱歉 巴裏 諾斯行動過早了
Well, you boys fucked me good.
哼 你們給我坑的不輕啊
We all got fucked.
我們都被坑了
Those photos weren't supposed to be released.
不該把那些照片公之於眾的
And certainly not until we had the Colombians in custody.
在我們抓到那幫哥倫比亞人之前肯定不會的
Yeah, well, he ain't gonna be comin' for you.
可他們不會找你報復啊
Barry, you knew the risks
巴裏 你拍那些照片的時候
when you took those pictures.
就知道這是有風險的
You knew what you were doing.
你當時清楚知道你在幹什麼
Barry?
巴裏？
Barry, you there?
巴裏 你還在聽嗎？
Let's go get some ice cream.
我們去買點兒冰激凌吧
The Feds. They're gonna try to take everything.
聯邦政府的人會拿走一切
When they come...
當他們來的時候
you gotta put on all your jewelry.
你必須把所有珠寶都戴在身上
All your rings. Your bracelets.
所有的戒指 手鐲
Necklace.
項鏈
If you wearin' it, they can't take it away from you.
如果你戴在身上 他們就不能從你身上搶走
You understand?
你明白嗎？
And that's insurance for you and the kids.
這是你和孩子未來的保障
All right?
懂嗎？
I understand.
我懂
All right, don't forget that. It's gonna be all right.
好 千萬別忘了 一切都會好起來的
- It's gonna be all right, I love you. - I love you.
- 一切都會好起來的 我愛你 - 我愛你
Sure enough, they came.
不出所料 他們果然來了
And they took it all.
然後他們拿走了一切
Hey, you know, Luce, honey...
嘿 露絲 寶貝
I was thinkin'...
我在想
that you might like to move back to Baton Rouge.
你還是搬回到巴吞魯日吧
You ain't gonna find nothin' in those drawers.
你在這些抽屜裏什麼也找不到的
Try the hat boxes, third shelf up.
去帽盒裏翻翻吧 第三個架子上
I mean, you loved it there.
我是說 你很喜歡住在那
What about you?
那你呢
I mean, I...
我啊
Me... Listen, see...
我 聽著
Look, if I run, they're uh...
聽著 如果我逃跑 他們會
They're gonna come for you and the kids. I mean...
他們會去找你和孩子們
That's how a thing like this goes.
他們辦事就是這個風格
But in Baton Rouge, you're safe.
但是在巴吞魯日 你們是安全的
No.
不
No, I ain't goin' nowhere.
我哪也不去
We're a family, and we're stayin' together.
我們是一家人 家人就應該在一起
- I know, but... - No, sir!
- 我知道 但是 - 我不
- I ain't doin' this. No. - Listen, Luce...
- 我就是不去那 - 聽著 露絲
No, no. Honey, no. Don't do this now.
不 親愛的 別這樣
Sir, sir, I'm sorry, no, no, no.
長官 不好意思 別別別
Come on, sir.
別這樣
Excuse me, she's wearin' this now.
不好意思 她正戴著這個呢
Luce, you gotta stop. Hey.
露絲 別鬧了
You know, fellas! Sorry, hey...
各位 抱歉
Can I just have a moment?
能給我點兒時間嗎？
Can I just have a moment with my wife?
可以讓我跟妻子獨處一會兒嗎？
It's been a hell of a day.
今天夠糟的了
- Okay, Barry. - Yeah.
- 好吧 巴裏 - 嗯
You got one minute.
你們只有一分鐘
All right, Luce? Honey, honey...
好吧 露絲？親愛的
- Honey, listen to me. - Let's give him a minute.
- 親愛的 聽我說 - 給他一分鐘
Baby, baby, listen to me.
寶貝 聽我說
- Listen to me now. - All right, fellas, head on out.
- 現在聽我說 - 來吧 我們出去
Ima go to prison.
我鐵定是要坐牢了
I'm gonna do just... just a little time.
我只會蹲一小段兒時間
And Ima be fine there.
我在監獄不會出問題的
And we'll work everything out.
我們會解決所有問題
But I gotta know you gonna be safe.
但是我必須得知道你們是安全的
It's gonna be all right.
不會有事的
You gotta trust me.
你得相信我
You trust me, right?
你相信我的 對吧？
Fuck no!
才他媽不呢
All right.
好啦
Luce and the kids finally did move to Baton Rouge.
露絲和孩子們最終搬到了巴吞魯日
How can we have a war on drugs...
毒品是我們最大的敵人
when the biggest enemy of the state
要是我們自己人都保護毒品交易
is being protected by our side?
那我們又怎能向毒品全面開戰呢？
And that lady prosecutor...
那個女檢察官
She never ever did give up.
她從沒放棄過
...such sting operation was underway.
這個誘捕行動正在進行中
The defendant will rise.
被告起立
- Barry Seal. - Your Honor.
- 巴裏·希爾 - 法官大人
You are sentenced to 1,000 hours community service.
你被判社區服務1000小時
Dismissed.
退庭
- Oh, that is bullshit. - Watch youself, Sibota.
- 這純他媽是扯淡 - 言辭 希伯塔
- I'm sorry, uh, community service? - ...a drug smuggler of the highest order!
- 不好意思 社區服務？- 一個最高級別的毒品走私犯
- Exhibit D! - Mr. Seal's planes are classified.
- 證據D - 希爾先生的飛機是被列入機密範疇的
- I'm sick to fuck of this Mickey Mouse... - Sibota!
- 我受夠了如此兒戲的 - 希伯塔
- tactics and bullshit! - Sibota!
- 策略和屁話 - 希伯塔
I will hold you in contempt!
我會判你藐視法庭
So I'm walkin' outta here? Now?
所以我現在是不是就可以走了？就現在？
The State of Arkansas has spoken, Mr. Seal.
阿肯色州最終判決已定 希爾先生
- Do I have to go? - Goodbye.
- 我必須得走嗎？- 再見
Listo pues.
準備動手吧
All right, amigos.
好的 弟兄們
And uh...
那個
I do tend to leap before I look.
我更傾向干了再說
Maybe uh...
或許啊
Maybe I should've asked a few more questions.
或許我該多問幾個問題的
Excuse me, Uh, sir, ma'am?
抱歉打擾下 先生 女士
Would y'all mind movin' out the way?
你們不介意能讓一下吧？
I'm just gonna start my car.
我要開車了
Yeah, I really appreciate that, now.
非常感謝
Honey, just keep walking.
親愛的 我們走吧
其化學反應沒什麼錯
Ain't nothing wrong with this chemistry
Thank you.
謝謝啦
- Just startin' my car. - Uh-huh.
- 我這就要開車了 - 好吧
Appreciate it.
非常感謝
時間能驗證血統的純正
And time will tell the test of pedigree
I spent every day in a different motel.
我每天住不同的汽車旅館
Would ya'll mind movin... movin' outta the way there?
你們介意讓開路嗎？
Thank you.
謝謝
告訴我該如何 該如何
And show me how (show me how)
A different motel.
又一家汽車旅館
Every day.
每天都換
如何成為一個好男人
What makes a good man?
It's just for the safety of children.
為了孩子的安全
Thank you.
謝謝
But I had to show up to this Salvation Army halfway house
但我每天必須去救贖軍人住宿站
every evening at the same time.
每晚的同一時間
Judge's orders.
法官的命令
You here for community service?
你來這做社區服務的？
Same time, same place.
同一時間 同一地點
Uh, what's your name? Sorry.
抱歉 你的名字是？
- Louis. - Louis? Barry Seal.
- 路易斯 - 路易斯啊？我叫巴裏·希爾
- Nice to meet you. - Nice to meet you.
- 很高興認識你 - 我也是
Sign here for me.
在這簽個字
120 days in a row. Here you go.
得在這干連續120天 這個給你
Hey, you may wanna move your truck too.
嘿 最好你也挪走你那輛卡車
Them Contras were damn excited about being in the US of A.
因為能留在美國 那些反抗軍非常的興奮
這個地方對我來說沒問題
Ain't nothing wrong with this place for me
嗨 巴裏
Hey, Barry.
When you gonna take me flyin', man?
你什麼時候帶我上飛機啊 哥們？
- Oh! Thanks, Barry. - Don't tell 'em I give you that.
- 謝謝你 巴裏 - 別跟比人說我給你這個了
Day 36.
第36天
沿著線走 沿著線走
And walk the line (walk the line)
然後去理解 理解
And understand (understand)
如何成為一個好男人
What makes a good man?
耶
Yeah
You know, I guess you could say I helped build an army.
我猜你想說我幫他們建了一個軍隊
Defend a country.
守衛國家
And create the biggest drug cartel this world's ever seen.
同時也創建了一個前無古人的最大販毒集團
DEA. CIA. White House.
緝毒局 中情局 白宮
I mean, it's been a hell of an adventure.
我想說 這段冒險歷程太刺激了
Sometimes a little more than I bargained for.
有時候我自己都受不了
But God damn.
但是 老天
You try tellin' me
你想告訴我
that this ain't the greatest country in the w...
這不是全世界最偉大的國家
We'll handle it from here, Deputy.
我們從這接手了 副警長
Authorities believe last night's machine-gun killing of Barry Seal
官方認為昨晚槍殺希爾
was ordered by drug bosses in Medellin, Colombia.
應是哥倫比亞麥德林城的販毒大佬下的命令
Iran.
伊朗
We get the Iranians to arm the Contras.
我們讓伊朗人將尼加拉瓜反抗軍武裝起來
"Schafer" was promoted.
"謝弗"高昇了
你個我了個哇-哇
You've given me a wah-wah
Pete became a rural pastor in Alabama after he was released.
皮特被釋放後在阿拉巴馬州的一個農村當牧師
The other pilots' whereabouts are unknown.
另一個飛行員的行蹤未知
The CIA continued using Barry's planes to arm the Contras.
中情局繼續用巴裏的飛機 來武裝資助尼加拉瓜反抗軍
Shit! Come on, you piece of shit! Pull up!
操 你個垃圾飛機 給老子拉起來啊
Until one of them was shot down in Nicaragua.
直到其中一架在尼加拉瓜境內被擊落
That sparked the Iran-Contra scandal.
這一事件激起了人們對伊朗門的關注
Mr. President, what do you know about money going to the Contras?
總統先生 資助反抗軍這件事您作何感想？
All I know is this is just gonna taste wonderful
我只知道這只火雞一定很美味
and I'm looking forward to tomorrow.
而且我對明天充滿期待
Vice President Bush, did you know about the Contra aid or not, sir?
布什副總統 您瞭解資助反抗軍的事嗎？
Lucy and the kids went back to Louisiana.
露絲和孩子們回到了路易斯安娜州
哇-哇
Wah-wah
Want some sauce with that?
要附帶調味醬嗎？
All right, thank you.
好的 謝謝